Jermaine varnicker



jvarnicker@yahoo.com



0780323334



linkedin.com/in/jvarnicker-varnicker-315a8794

Summary

Experienced Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the banking industry. Skilled in Data Wrangling, Python, Statistical Data Analysis, Big Data Analytics, Data Science, and Data Visualization, Data modelling, T-SQL. Strong financial crimes professional with a Specialization focused in Data science.

Experience

Fraud Analyst

FNB South Africa

Feb 2016 - Present (5 years 4 months +)

- -Charge Backs- Accurate processing of charge backs in line with applicable codes which comply with the appropriate payment system (e.g. Visa and MasterCard) rules.
- -Fraud Document Compilation and Supply- Timely, accurate checking and comprehensive compilation and supply of fraud related documentation in the required format to support efforts in addressing identified fraud events.
- -Service Delivery- Deliver exceptional service that exceeds customers' expectations through proactive, innovative and appropriate solutions.
- -Arbitration- Execute activities for arbitration of cases by preparing required information, which includes controlled sharing of customer information between banks, engaging with various stakeholders to validate any transactions.
- -Case Recording and Monitoring- Recording and/or monitoring of fraud cases in internal and external databases.
- -Fraud Information- Timely and accurate recording and checking of fraud related information to disseminate to relevant stakeholders.
- -Fraud Process, Rules and System Compliance- Execute fraud administration duties in line with required rules, processes and using available systems. Ensure that activities are executed in a timely manner and accuracy.
- -Operational Losses- Contribute to the reduction in operational losses by providing efficient administrative support to the fraud team.
- -Recoveries- Execute recovery activities in line with applicable standards and laws to maximize recoveries for the Bank.
- -Reporting Fraud Support- Compile and communicate accurate and timely reports on fraud according to area of focus.

Reference: Ntombi Lebuso (manager)

Tell: 087 311 2377

fraud analyst

FNB South Africa

Jan 2011 - Feb 2016 (5 years 2 months)

- -Fraud Detection, Analyzing fraud via AI and visa online system
- -Meeting of targets to contact customers with regards to possible fraud.

- -Opening of new fraud cases for Debit and cheque card fraud.
- -Updating customer's fraud cases on customer profile.
- -Following up on existing cases Card cancellations.
- -Receive calls from internal & external customers.
- -Confirmations of fraudulent transactions from other banks
- -Customer Service
- -Hot listing of Cards and send affidavits to customer.

Reference: Nirvana Ramboth (HR manager)

Tell: 087 311 7557

IT Field Technician

JNT Computers (PTY) Ltd

Jun 2015 - Apr 2016 (11 months)

Performing backups and installing hardware

Installing printers and administering user accounts

Ensuring adherence to quality standards in the organisation

Troubleshooting and resolving technical errors

Attending to ad hoc tasks and requests

Maintaining of technological trends and developments

Appointed as a computer service and maintenance technician

Performing software installations and upgrades

Installing, configuring and providing support on network connections

Assisting with ad hoc technical assignments as required

Education



Silver Oak Senior Secondary

High School Diploma, Matric

2002 - 2006

Subjects:

- -English
- -Afrikaans
- -Mathematics
- -Science
- -Biology
- -Accountancy



CTU Training Solutions

National Certificate: Information Technology (Systems Development), Data science

2020 - 2021 Modules:

-Principles of Program Design: PPD511

- -Relational Database Development: RDD511
- -Database Programming DBP511
- -Introduction to Statistics IS512

-Introduction to data science: IDS512

-Big Data Analysis: BDA512 -Python Programming -PP512

Licenses & Certifications

Exam 761: Querying Data with Transact-SQL - Microsoft 990707958

Skills

Machine Learning • Transact-SQL (T-SQL) • Data Science • Statistical Data Analysis • Credit Cards • Mathematical Programming • Python (Programming Language) • Database Design • Big Data Analytics • Neural Networks